difference-engine.com 2016-02-10

# Privacy Policy « Difference Engine

**Learning Objects, Inc.**

**Privacy Policy  **

Learning Objects, Inc. (“ **Learning Objects,** ” “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”) provides an online platform, a set of applications, and related technology designed to permit education providers to create tailored learning environments for students and other end users (collectively, “ **Students** “).  Our subscribers include colleges, universities, K-12 schools, publishers, and education technology providers (“ **Subscribers** “).  Our products are provided to Students through our relationships with Subscribers and other partners. Learning Objects is committed to safeguarding the privacy of its Subscribers and Students. The following privacy policy governs our privacy practices for each of our products.

**Our Compliance With Applicable Law**

Our products are designed for students enrolled in a college, university, or K-12 school system.  We recognize the sensitive nature of personal information, for example (a) concerning Students under age 13 that is protected under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“ **COPPA** ”), and (b) concerning information in a Student’s educational records that is protected under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, including the Protection of Pupil Rights Amendment (“ **FERPA** “).  We also recognize the range of other regulations concerning privacy and information security.  Our privacy practices comply with COPPA and FERPA, as well as with other applicable privacy laws.  We comply both with respect to personal information we store, as well as personal information we ourselves collect or receive from Subscribers in the course of providing our products and services.

**The Scope of Our Privacy Policy**

Our privacy policy describes: (i) what personal information we collect on our own behalf and receive from our Subscribers; (ii) how we use that information; (iii) with whom we share that information; and (iv) what steps we take to safeguard this information. This policy governs not only our practices with respect to students’ personal information, but also with respect to the personal information of all other users of our products, including teachers and others.

**How We Ask for Your Consent to Our Privacy Policy**

We ask for consent to (a) collect and use Students’ personal information and to (b) collect and use personal information of all other users of our products, as described below.

**Consent from Schools regarding Students’ Personal Information**

For purposes of compliance with COPPA, we rely on schools to obtain proper Student consent, as permitted under COPPA. For purposes of compliance with FERPA, we rely on the law’s “school official” exception. This privacy policy is consistent with our obligations as a “school official”.

**Consents from Other Users  **

Finally, we may obtain consents from users other than those covered by Section 3.1 (Consent from Schools regarding Students’ Personal Information).  To obtain these consents we (a) notify the users of our privacy practices by including links to this privacy policy on our website, (b) rely on their continued use of our products to indicate their consent to this privacy policy, and (c) rely on consents obtained from our partners who have directly contracted with such users.

**The Types of User Information We Collect**

We provide a platform for Subscribers to provide strong educational experiences for their users.   To enable a greater customization and individualized experience for students, teachers, and other users, personal information may be gathered through use of our products, or through integration of our products with that of a Subscriber with whom the user has contracted.  We limit our collection of personal information to no more than is reasonably necessary for our users — including students, teachers, school administrators and parents — to participate in our products, and no more than is permitted for improvements permitted by COPPA and FERPA.

The following types of information may be collected through your use of our products:

  * Full Name
  * Email Address
  * Information concerning the Student or the Student’s parents combined with another identifier
  * Screen/usernames where they function in the same manner as online contact information
  * Student educational records
  * Pages visited and the time spent on each page
  * Articles read
  * Search terms or other data entered on the online platform
  * User information such as preferred language and Web-browser type, operating system, and geographical location information
  * Information that is not linked or reasonably linkable to an individual or to a particular device
  * Content supplied by the users through participation in our platform

**How We Collect Personal Information  **

We collect personal information during the registration process and during the normal operation of our products, including through integration with our partners. In addition, our products collect usage information through technology, such as cookies, flash cookies, web beacons, and persistent identifiers.

**Third Party Collection**

For certain products, we contract directly with the school or other Subscriber. For other products, we act as a service provider to a third party, and that third party has the direct relationship with the school (or other Subscriber) (each such Subscriber-facing entity, a “ **Primary Provider** “). Learning Objects relies on the Subscriber to select their Primary Providers, and to confirm that the privacy and information security practices of these Primary Providers meet the school’s (or other Subscriber’s) requirements.  This Policy does not address, and Learning Objects is not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of Primary Providers and their other service providers.

**How We Use Personal Information**

We use personal information for the following purposes:

  * To provide users with the content and features available through our products;
  * To communicate with school administrators, teachers, and parents about the applicable subscription account or transactions with us, and to send information about our products’ features and where applicable, changes to these features;
  * To personalize our products’ content and experiences for students, teachers, and other users of the platform;
  * To detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal;
  * To authenticate and identify users;
  * When you direct us to share your personal information with third-party sites or platforms, such as social networking sites; and
  * To integrate our products with those of Primary Providers.

As noted in Section 6 (Third Party Collection), we do not as a rule allow third-party operators, other than Primary Providers, to collect personal information or usage information through persistent identifiers on our products for any purposes other than to provide and operate our products and services.

Finally, we de-identify usage information in accordance with COPPA and FERPA, and use this de-identified information to develop, evaluate, and provide improved educational products and services, as permitted under COPPA and FERPA.

**We Use Personal Information For Internal Purposes Only, And Do Not Share Personal Information Beyond Our Products**

We share our user’s personal information in the following limited instances.  First, we share information with our Vendors if necessary for them to perform a business, professional, or technology support function for us.  In instances where we engage Vendors for these purposes, we require them to comply with this privacy policy.  Moreover, we require our Vendors by contract to comply with COPPA, FERPA, and other privacy-related applicable law.  Second, we disclose personal information if necessary

  * in response to a law enforcement or an authorized public agency’s request, including a request by a school or children’s services agency;
  * if we believe disclosure may prevent the instigation of a crime, facilitate an investigation related to public safety or protect the safety of a student or other user of our products;
  * to protect the security or integrity of our products and associated applications and technology, as well as the technology of our Vendors;
  * to enable us to take precautions against liability, enforce legal rights, and to detect, investigate and prevent activities that violate our policies or that are illegal;
  * in other cases if we believe in good faith that disclosure is required by law; and
  * to an acquirer in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings), provided that such disclosure is subject to this privacy policy.

**How We Protect Personal Information  **

We have implemented commercially reasonable technical, administrative and physical security controls, including transport layer security, data encryption, and select multi-factor authentication, designed to protect personal information from unauthorized access, disclosure, use or modification.

**Access and Control of Personal Information**

We provide two methods for accessing and correcting personal information used in our products — one method is for personal information of students, and the other is for personal information of users other than students.

Parents and guardians of students who wish to review, correct, or update their child’s personal information stored on our products should contact their child’s school. We cooperate with and facilitate the school’s response to these access requests. Eligible Students, as that term is defined by FERPA, can obtain this information in a similar manner. We provide users other than students and parents — such as teachers and schools — similar access and deletion rights.  Users should be aware that deletions of personal information will prevent the user from engaging in some or likely all features of our products.

**Our Retention and Deletion of Personal Information**

We will retain personal information of users of our products, including Students, only so long as reasonably necessary to permit the user to participate in the platform, and ensure the security of our users and our services, or as required by law.  After this period has expired, we will delete the personal information from our systems.

**Notice to California Residents**

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by Learning Objects to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  As described above, we do not disclose users’ personal information to third parties to direct marketing purposes.  Nevertheless, if you wish to make such a request, please send an email to or write us at:

Attention: Legal  
Email: [jmarashi@learningobjects.com](mailto:jmarashi@learningobjects.com)  
Mail: Learning Objects, Inc.  
1528 Connecticut Ave NW, Washington DC 20036

**Do Not Track Notice**

Certain web browsers allow consumers to enable “do not track” signals through which a consumer can signal to websites and online services whether the consumer approves of the collection of personally identifiable information about its online activities over time and across third-party websites and online services. Learning Objects does not respond to “do not track” signals.

**Further Information**

For more information about protections for students’ and children’s personal information, please visit:

The Federal Trade Commission: <http://www.business.ftc.gov/privacy-and-security/childrens-privacy>

The Department of Education: <http://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/brochures/parents.html>

**Updates  **

As circumstances warrant, we may change this Policy.  With respect to partners or schools with whom we have a written contract, such changes will become effective upon renewal of such contract, or if the partner or school otherwise agrees.  With respect to other users, changes will become effective upon the user’s consent, in the manner set forth in Section 3.2 (Consents from Other Users).

**Definitions**

“De-identified information” means information that meets each of the following criteria:  the information (i) does not identify a particular natural person; (ii) does not identify, by network Internet Protocol address, raw hardware serial number, or raw MAC address, a particular device or computer associated with or used by a person; (iii) does not identify the school at issue by name or address; and (iv) is not reasonably linkable to a particular natural person or school because of technical, legal, or other controls.

“Personal information” means information that identifies (whether directly or indirectly) a particular individual, such as the individual’s name, postal address, email address and telephone number. When Usage Information is directly or indirectly associated with personal information, this Usage Information also is treated as personal information.

“Usage Information” means information that does not directly identify a particular person, but that may be linkable to a particular computer or device (via a unique device ID or otherwise).

“We” or “us” or “our” refers to Learning Objects.

**Contact Us**

You may contact us with questions or concerns with respect to this Privacy Policy at the following addresses:

Attention: Legal  
Email: [jmarashi@learningobjects.com](mailto:jmarashi@learningobjects.com)  
Mail: Learning Objects, Inc.  
1528 Connecticut Ave NW, Washington DC 20036

**Effective Date**

The effective date of this privacy policy is June 5, 2014.
